Damla Mazlum Celikbas (she/her/hers)

Cloud Engineer

AWS re/Start program graduate . Achieved AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner in April 2021 and currently working towards to become AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate.

Results-driven software developer and AWS Cloud Engineer who have a passion for Cloud Technologies seeking to use proven Python, JSON, Linux and Core AWS Services knowledge to deliver coding excellence and cloud computing solutions.

Before deciding to make a career change, worked as a Senior Project Management Engineer with 9 years of experience managing variety of projects.

Work History

2021-01 - 2021-04

AWS re/Start Trainee

AWS

- Completed 12 week, full-time, classroom based skills development and training program on IT fundamentals, AWS Cloud, and professional skills.
- Built IT fundamental skills, including: working knowledge of Linux OS, writing scripts in Python and Shell and data querying in MySQL completed 70 labs
- Learned how to apply core AWS services in the area of compute, storage and networking, including EC2 (and LAMP stack), S3, IAM, VPC, Lamda, Cloud Formation, Cloud Watch / SNS, RDS, Cloud Trail and Route 53.
- Completed 30 AWS Labs in AWS Management Console and AWS CLI architecting AWS Cloud environments based on case studies
- Gained strong troubleshooting skills
- Demonstrated strong verbal, written and presentational communication skills, including the ability to explain technical information and terminology to non-technical end users e. Learned how to configure, monitor and support the suite of core AWS services.

2019-12 - 2020-09

Senior Project Engineer

Alten Ltd UK

- Consultant Engineer in Air Intake Systems (AIS) team in Jaguar Land Rover.
- Lead project management of team of 8 component engineers.
- Managed team goals and metrics.
- Represented the team working with multifunctional teams to ensure programme deliverables are met on time, scope and cost.
- Confirm and communicate programme assumptions and changes to the AIS team.

2019-02

Design and Release Engineer

- 2019-04 RLE International UK

- Consultant Engineer in Body Closures team in Aston Martin Lagonda.
- Responsible for development and delivery of components (Decklid, Decklid Hinges and Gas Strut) on time to cost, weight and PSW targets.
- Support the management and coordination of engineering deliverables
- Resolved technical conflicts to programme requirements as per Gateway deliverables process in a timely manner.

2018-04

- 2019-02

Cost Reduction Engineer

RLE International UK

• Consultant Engineer in Body Structures and Body in White Cost Reduction

Personal Info

Email

damlamzlm@gmail.com

Phone

+44 7985 492713

Address

134 Batsford Road CV6 1AU Coventry

Skills

Aws Core services

Linux

Python programming language

MySQL

Project management

HTML, CSS, JS

C# Programming Language

JSON/YAML

Time management

Communication

Problem solving

Windows

Ms office suite

Cost reduction

Benchmarking

Certificates

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Issued Apr 2021 - Expires Apr 2024

5 Day Coding Challenge by Code Institute - August 2020

HTML,CSS,JS

Project Management

Yildiz Technical University & Istanbul Institute - 2011

Advanced Sales Techniques and Persuasion Methods

Istanbul 2012

- team in Aston Martin Lagonda.
- Lead 25 cost reduction projects from concept to product introduction.
- Developed detailed project plans to ensure cross-functional resource availability and allocation for approved cost-reduction projects.
- Kick off each project and review the timing with all stakeholders within in the company and suppliers.
- During project design development phase, created 'Engineering Design
 Decision Matrix' in order to decide the best design and financial return for the business.
- Managed changes to the project scope, project schedule and project costs using appropriate verification techniques

2017-09 - 2018-04

Product Development Engineer

Jaguar Land Rover

- Responsible for development of Brake Pads
- Managed engineering design and releasing using JLR systems (AIMS, PACN, WERS)
- Applied Failure Mode Avoidance techniques (FMEA)
- Managed Design Verification Plan for testing conducted at the supplier and at JLR
- Analysed test reports/data and recorded in RMDV.

2014-11 - 2017-09

Project Support Engineer

Jaguar Land Rover

- Worked as a Cross Car Line Support Engineer in Foundation Brakes
 Engineering team and worked ~10 vehicle programmes at a time
- Increased efficiency within the team by rolling out internal processes and documents
- Created 'Part Number Complexity Matrix ' and rolled out updates to ensure part details for each programme and build is correct and up-to-date
- Created 'Requirement Management Complexity Matrix' to plan gateway timing of tests and part requirement for each test.
- · Lead Cost Reduction (TVM) Projects.

2014-03 - 2014-10

Business Planner

Jaguar Land Rover

- Lead VLBR (Vehicle Line Business Review) projects, managed work streams and delivery of opportunities
- Benchmark competitor vehicles and analyse to capture opportunities
- Assisted in the development of business cases to ensure activities have a
 positive impact on vehicle line profitability.
- Prepared PDL (Product Direction Letter) documentation for handover to the relevant programme team for implementation.

2011-04 - 2013-06

Sales and Marketing Engineer

CVS Technologies

- Managed the development and production of proposal responses to requests for proposals/quotations (RFPs / RFQs)
- Analyzed RFP requirements and prepared proposal outlines.
- Travelled to visit potential and existing clients in Europe.
- Provided technical and engineering information to clients
- · Liaised with key stakeholders to develop scope of work and strategy

Education

- 2010-06

Yildiz Technical University, Istanbul

B. Eng., Mechanical Engineering

Courses

MySQL

Codecadamy 2020

C#

By kodlama.io - practiced in Visual Studio 2019

Braking of Road Vehicles

TAS Module - University of Bradford - 2015

AutoCad

TMMOB (Chamber of Mechanical Engineers Turkey)

Hobby

Learning new Programming Languages
Nature Photography
Hiking
Gardening